Ow!
(ナルト)いって～！
くぅ！ いててて…。
Owww...
(フカサク)もっと集中せんか！
Focus!
Though it's just a little,
your body is moving!
体が わずかだが動いとる。
「動くな」を忘れるな。
Don't forget, "stay still"!
油を使わねえと
こうも難しいとは➡
Doing this without using the oil
is a lot harder than I thought.
思わなかったってばよ。
あったりまえじゃ！
Of course it is!
Don't expect it'll be so easy
when you don't use the oil!
油なしで
そう簡単にいくと思うなや！
微動だにもしては いけん。
Not even the slightest quiver!
Say, I was just thinking...
あのさ ちょっち思ったんだけど。
なんじゃ？
What is it?
Why can't I just take this oil
with me when I fight?
戦うときは ここの油を
持って行けばいいじゃん。
Then I won't need to learn
そうすりゃ 自然エネルギーを➡
how to take in Nature Energy
without the oil.
油なしでとりこむ修業も
必要ねえし。
そりゃ ムリじゃ。
えっ なんで？
That is impossible.
Huh? Why?
Outside of Mount Myoboku's climate,
this oil vaporizes immediately.
ここの油は
妙木山の気候以外では➡
すぐに気化してしまうんじゃ。
えっ そうなの？
No kidding?!
I thought I told you.
言うたはずじゃ。
The oil is only to help you
grasp the concept.
油は きっかけを
つかむためのものじゃと。
オッス！
Yes, sir!
But the way you change
into a frog so quickly...
だいたい
こうも簡単に カエル化するとは…。
Naruto-boy, you lack concentration!
ナルトちゃんは まだ集中力が 甘い。
ナメきっとる！
You're not taking it
seriously enough!
いや そんなことは。
No, that's not true.
After all, I did get the knack of
this thing from the previous training.
こう見えても
修業するノウハウなら 前の修業で…。
Enough! Just follow me!
いいから！ わしに ついてこい！
あのさ まさかとは思うけど…。
Hey... This isn't what
I'm thinking, is it?
そのとおり。
ここが次の修業場じゃ。
It's exactly that.
This is your next training site.
あのてっぺんに石板をのせ
座禅を組む。
Stack a stone slab atop that summit
and begin Zen meditation.
If your concentration wavers
and you move even slightly,
集中を乱し わずかでも動けば➡
谷底まで転がり落ちる
という寸法じゃ。
you will fall to the bottom
of the ravine.
あ あそこから…。
F-From up there?
Hmm... This should do.
ふむ… ちょうど
このくらいじゃのう。
ナルトちゃんも続け！
Follow me, Naruto-boy!
Stay still!
動くな！ 動物としての流れを
止めるのじゃ。
You must learn to stop
your motion as an animal.
バランスのとれる一点を
己で見つけだし➡
Find your own center of balance,
動かず自然と調和せい。
and motionlessly synchronize
with nature!
うおっ たっ とっ…。
うわあ！
た 助かった…。
S-Saved.
自然エネルギーをとりこむのは➡
Taking in Nature Energy
will have to wait
until you first perfect staying still.
「動くな」が できてからじゃな。
うわあ… あ ああ！
ウソ!?
No way!
Oww...
たはは…。
はぁ 少し休憩にするかのう。
Maybe it's time for a break.
くそっ…。
Damn...
「動くな」だけで
こんなに難しいなんて。
It's this hard just to stay still...
Isn't this training sorta ridiculous?
この修業 ちょっと
ムチャすぎなんじゃねえか？
何を言っとるか。
Such nonsense!
Your master, Jiraiya-boy,
managed this feat.
ナルトちゃんの師匠 自来也ちゃんは
ちゃんと やり遂げたぞ。
え？ もしかして➡
Huh? Don't tell me...
Pervy Sage trained here too?
エロ仙人も ここで修業したの？
ああ ワシと２人で
ずいぶん通ったもんじゃ。
Yes. He and I came here often.
((自来也 : ヘヘ サンキュー フカサク様！
Thank you, Lord Fukasaku!
のう 自来也ちゃんよ
今日は もうやめとくか？
Say Jiraiya-boy,
how about we call it a day?
いいや オレは
まだまだ 大丈夫だぜ！
Nah! I can still keep on going.
ニヒヒヒ！
しかし…。
But...
もう少しで
何か つかめそうなんだ。
I think I'm on the verge
of grasping it...
(もうしばらく つきあってくれよ))
So can you help me for
a while longer?
本当に ど根性だけは
人一倍じゃったわい。
I must say, he had more guts
than anybody else around.
なあ この修業 エロ仙人は
どれぐらいかかったんだ？
Say, how long did Pervy Sage
take on this training?
自来也ちゃんの場合
任務の間に➡
Well, Jiraiya-boy came here to
train between missions,
人間界と行き来しながらの
修業じゃったからの。
それなりに月日が かかったが。
そっか。
so it took him some time...
I see.
ナルトちゃん。
Naruto-boy?
影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
オレには時間がねえ。
だから ペースアップしねえと。
I don't have the luxury of time.
So I have to pick up the pace!
エロ仙人がやった修業だからな
オレも がんばんねえと！
Pervy Sage did the same training!
So I've gotta do my best too!
Surpassing the Master
うわ～っ！
It's no good...
ああ ダメだ。
Focus, Naruto-boy!
ナルトちゃん もっと集中せい。
That's pretty colorful
and yummy looking.
なんか カラフルで うまそうだな。
おお ナルトちゃんも食うかい？
Oh, would you like one, Naruto-boy?
ワシの大好物の幼虫おにぎりじゃ。
It's my favorite, larva riceballs.
No thanks!
デーッ！ いいってばよ！
Oh no!
(ガマ吉)うわっ まずい！
おお！
Oh...
《いい感じじゃ。 自然エネルギーが
どんどん集まっとる》
It's looking good.
He's rapidly amassing Nature Energy.
《とうとう やりおった！
He's finally got it!
I'm impressed at how far
he's gotten without using the oil.
油を使わず ここまで
できるようになるとはのう》
《仙人の証し 隈取りが出とる。
He's displaying the rings around
the eyes. Proof of Sagehood.
カエル化も まったくしておらん。
And no frog aspects either!
ナルトちゃんは 自来也ちゃんを凌ぐ
仙人になったということかいな。
This might mean Naruto-boy
has become a Sage,
surpassing Jiraiya-boy!
And it seems he's able to build up
それに油を使ったときより➡
even more Sage Jutsu chakra
than when he was using the oil.
さらに 大きな仙術チャクラを
練れとるようじゃ》
どんな感じじゃ？
How does it feel?
うん 自然と一体になるって
こんな感じなのかなって。
Hmm... Now I kinda get what it means
to become one with nature.
あ… あっ！
ああ～っ！
あいててて…。
Owwww...
って あれ？ あんまり痛くねえ。
Huh? It doesn't hurt that much...
それが仙人モードじゃ。
And that is Sage Mode!
体があらゆる意味で
活性化されとる。
Your body has been activated
on many levels.
W-Wow! Sage Mode, huh?!
すっげぇ 仙人モード！
Now that you've mastered
Sage Mode,
さて 仙人モードもできたことじゃし
最後のステップじゃな。
we've come to the final step.
What?! Final step?
You mean there's more?!
え!? 最後のステップって
まだ何かあんの？
仙人が仙術チャクラを使って
行う組み手➡
It's a type of sparring
that Sages perform using
Sage Jutsu chakra.
Now I shall teach you
how to do Frog Kumite!
蛙組み手の戦い方を
叩き込んじゃる番じゃ！
(水月)もう～ 使えないな。
You are so useless!
Why'd you leave behind
my Executioner's Blade?!
なんでボクの首切り包丁を
置いてきたんだよ！
Shut up, Suigetsu!
(香燐)うるせぇぞ 水月！
Just be thankful
we didn't leave you behind!
テメエを連れ帰っただけでも
ありがたく思え！
Look who's talking!
You were also passed out, Karin!
何だよ その言い草
香燐だって気絶してたくせに！
I got knocked out trying
to protect you guys!
ウチは アンタらを守って
そうなったんだよ！
(重吾)お互いをかばいあって
そうなった。
It's the result of us trying
to protect each other.
オレたちは
水魚の交わりと言うべき仲間だ。
We're like fish and water,
so close we can't do
without one another.
そう いがみ合うな。
So quit quarreling.
わかったよ。
Fine.
By the way, are we really
going to get
ところで 本当に尾獣の力は
もらえるのか？ サスケ。
the Tailed Beast's power, Sasuke?
Hmph. Who knows?
(サスケ)フッ どうだろうな。
But it seems there's no need
to rely on that anymore.
だが そんな力に頼る必要は
なくなったようだ。
なんで？
Why?
《オレは新しい力を手に入れた。
I have obtained new powers...
Strong enough to destroy
the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉を潰せる十分な力を》
どうした？ サスケ。
What's wrong, Sasuke?
何でもない。
It's nothing.
どうした？ 香燐。
外にチャクラを感じる。
What is it, Karin?
I sense a chakra outside.
It seems we've been tailed.
どうやら
つけられていたようだな。
ほら 行け。
Now, go!
すみません 雷影様。
Forgive me, Lord Raikage...
どうやら 尾行は失敗のようです。
It appears my tail was unsuccessful.
Not only Yugito,
but now Bee too...
(雷影)ユギトだけでなく ビーまでも…。
ビーがやられるなど信じられん！
I cannot believe that Bee
has been taken down!
ジェイからの連絡トカゲが➡
We have been receiving several
messenger lizards from Jay.
先程から何匹か
送られてきています。
Once we've pinpointed
the enemy's whereabouts,
敵の居場所がわかりしだい
四小隊を送り込み➡
we'll send in four cells to
rescue Lord Killer Bee,
キラービー様を救出し
敵を殲滅します。
and wipe out the enemy.
弟をさらったのは➡
I heard it was an Uchiha
from the Hidden Leaf
あの木ノ葉隠れの
うちはの者だと聞いたが➡
who kidnapped my little brother!
なぜ うちはの者が暁におる？
Why is there an Uchiha
in the Akatsuki?!
うちはサスケ もう随分と前に➡
Sasuke Uchiha...
It appears he went rogue
from the Hidden Leaf
木ノ葉の抜け忍に
なっていたようです。
quite some time ago.
木ノ葉の火影は なぜ さっさと
抜け忍を始末しない？
Why hasn't the Leaf's Hokage dealt
with this Rogue Ninja?!
日向の件では
あれだけ したたかだった里が！
They were so quick to react
over the Hyuga incident!
《おかしい…
先輩からの連絡が途絶えた》
Something's wrong...
The messages have ceased.
ナルトちゃんよ
今日は ここまでじゃ。
Naruto-boy, let's call it a day.
まだまだ！
No, not yet!
これ以上は ワシがもたん。
I'm the one that can't go on.
However...you're starting to
get the hang of it.
じゃが だいぶ
コツがつかめてきたようじゃのう。
オッス！
Yes, sir!
なんだと!?
What?!
ジェイからの連絡が途絶えたとは
いったいどういうことだ？
What do you mean the messages
from Jay have ceased?!
ジェイは どうやら殺されたか
拘束されたようですね。
It seems Jay has either
been killed or captured.
これで 敵の居場所が
特定できなくなりました。
So we're unable to confirm
the enemy's location.
いままでの情報から
ある程度の居場所を割り出して➡
Use whatever information we have
to narrow down the location,
シラミ潰しに探させろ！
and search every inch
of the place!
一個大隊を出しても構わん！
I don't care if you have
to dispatch a battalion!
わ わかりました。
それから サムイの小隊を呼べ。
Y-Yes sir.
Summon Samui's platoon too!
うちはサスケを こちらで
始末する旨の書面を持たせて➡
I'm giving them
a document of intent to
deliver to the Hidden Leaf
木ノ葉へ向かわせる。
stating that we will take care
of Sasuke Uchiha!
ソイツの情報も出させろ！
はい ただちに！
And have them give us
intel on him!
Yes, right away!
さらに 忍五大国
五影首脳会談の段取りをつける。
Furthermore, I'm going to convene
a Five Kage Summit Conference
with the Five Great Nations!
暁は 絶対に許さん！
The Akatsuki will not be forgiven!
(サムイ)オモイ カルイ 雷影様から
お呼びがかかったわよ。
Omoi, Karui...
Lord Raikage has summoned us.
(カルイ)呼び出しねえ。
Summoned, eh?
(オモイ)いったい
なんだというんだ？
What in the world could it be?
もしかしたら 大変なことが？
Maybe there's a crisis...
それとも なにか？
叱られるのか？
Or maybe... We're getting scolded?
最近 体脂肪率が高くなってること
ばれたのか？
Did he find out that my body fat
percentage has spiked?
やっぱ ポテトにマヨネーズつけて食べたの
ダメだったのか？
Maybe eating potatoes with
mayonnaise wasn't a good idea?
オモイ お前は
いつも考え過ぎなんだよ。
Omoi, you always think too much!
そんなことで叱られっかよ！
Why would he scold you
for something like that?!
どうせ プロテインの買いだめに
行かされるぐらいだよ。
The most that would happen is
you could get sent to
buy some protein.
フンッ アンタたちといると疲れるね。
Being around you guys
is so tiring.
ああ 肩がこる。
Makes my shoulders ache.
肩こりは 恐らく
その大きな胸が原因だろうけど➡
The stiff shoulders are probably
caused by those big breasts of yours,
そうとも言い切れないこともある。
although one can't say for sure.
ただの肩こりと思っていたことが
実は…。
What you thought was just
a stiff shoulder could actually...
あ～ うっせえよ もう
ウダウダ言ってねえで 行こうぜ！
Will you shut up!
Quit yakking and let's go!
ものごとは
もっと慎重に考えるべきだ。
You ought to think things
through more carefully.
胸のないカルイに
肩こりがないにしても。
A flat-chested person like you
may not get stiff shoulders, Karui, but...
うるっせえんだよ！
イタイ！
Shut up!
Oww! Now that kick will cause...
そのキックが…。
まだ言うか！
You got more to say?!
ほら ２人とも忍者なら
もっとクールになさい 行くわよ。
You two...
If you're ninja, act cooler.
Let's go!
どうにか できたってばよ。
I pulled it off!
といっても
まだまだ完璧じゃねえ。
Even though it's far from perfect...
もっと 仙人モードで練習しねえと。
I need more practice while
in Sage Mode.
それに 誰にも
見られないようにしねえとな。
And, I have to make sure
no one sees me.
ジェイ…。
遅かったか。
Jay...
We were too late.
TO HOKAGE
FROM RAIKAGE
では 確かに。
頼んだぞ。
Mission acknowledged.
I'm counting on you!
やっぱり 嫌な予感がしたんだ
クソ！
I knew it...
I had a bad feeling about this.
Damn!
大丈夫だよ あのキラービー様が
ヘマこくわけないだろ。
Don't worry!
No way Lord Killer Bee would
screw up like that.
どうせ何かの悪い冗談だって。
It's probably some bad joke.
なんで そんなに楽観的なんだ。
How can you be optimistic?!
今も
苦しんでらっしゃるかもしれない。
He could be suffering right
this moment!
もしかすると もう…。
In fact, he could already...
うるせえ！ そんな悲観的な
テメエの考えは聞きたかねえんだよ。
Shut up! I don't want to hear
your pessimistic thoughts!
私らの師だぞ
あのキラービー様だぞ。
He's our master!
We're talking about
Lord Killer Bee here!
やられるわけねえんだよ。
There's no way he'd be defeated!
カルイは ビー様が心配じゃないのか！
Aren't you worried about Lord Bee, Karui?
心配だからって
勝手な妄想するんじゃねえ！
Don't get morbid ideas just
because you're worried!
よせ お前たち。
Enough, you two!
ビーは どんな手を使っても助ける
助けるぞ！
We'll save Bee,
no matter what it takes!
We will save him!
《２人 : 雷影様…》
- Lord Raikage!
なかなか
やるようになったのう！
Ah! You've made great progress!
Nice, Naruto-boy.
That's some jumping power.
Your Frog Kumite is
also pretty good!
Heh... That's not all!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
はぁ！
いいぞ ナルトちゃん。
たいしたジャンプ力じゃ。
蛙組み手も
なかなかのもんじゃのう。
ヘッ それだけじゃねえってばよ。
影分身の術！
えっ？
まだまだ これからだってばよ！
かかってきんしゃい！
はあ！
＜改ざんＢ－ＣＡＳカードによる
不正視聴は➡
刑法により禁じられた犯罪行為＞
＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
(ナツ)来いよ！
(バイロ)ぬ…？ 部品が…。
(ミッシェル)呼応している…。
動くのか… 刻が…。
おぉ… 混沌が…。
永遠の真夜中が… 来る！